Iosh Shone

Full-stack software developer

Sept. 26, 1989

@ josh.shone@gmail.com

s iosh.shone

joshshone.com

+49 1765 793 7870 Perlin

Hi, I'm Josh - a full-stack web and native applications developer living in Berlin (originally from Canberra, Australia). I have around 9 years experience, covering UX/UI design, native applications, low-level multimedia processing and modern HTML5/IS using Agile.

Employment

2016 - 2018 KIWI.KI GmbH 2 years, 6 months

Full-stack web developer



Developed and released an overhauled version of KIWI's web app for housing companies, covering backend work in Python/Flask and frontend work in node.js/backbone. Also implemented user experience improvements to KIWI's consumer web frontend.

General Dynamics Mediaware

2012 - 2015 3 years, 4 months

■ Native application programmer
■ Web developer

Q Canberra, Australia

Initial role as C++ programmer engaged in performance analysis, debugging and feature development on a large codebase. Worked in a mid-sized Agile team adhering to well-defined processes for issue-tracking, continuous integration, customer feedback and development iterations.

Helped develop the company's flagship product InStream, a high-performance multi-threaded video processing service for broadcast television. Also engaged in R&D, producing working prototypes for new products - one of which went on to be used by Australian firefighting services.

Took on a new role as primary web developer after showing initiative by producing performance analysis tooling with HTML5. Went on to develop a company-wide framework for service control utilizing cutting-edge web standards including websocket-based RPC (WAMP) and reactor-based networking (Twisted). Was also responsible for UI design, mockups, user-testing and producing high-quality documentation.

NCH Software

2009 - 2012 3 years, 4 months

UI Designer
 Native application developer

Q Canberra, Australia

Was responsible for creating several native desktop applications from scratch, including a non-destructive photo editor and musical notation software. Initial concept, design, mockups, prototyping, development and release was handled either solo or in small teams. Highlights:

- Designed a unique modeless editing UI for sheet music.
- Implemented a dynamic level-of-detail system for smoothly scaling fast fourier transform visualizations.
- Developed a high-performance non-destructive image transformation and layering system.

Education

Academy of Interactive Entertainment

Canberra, Australia

2007 - 2008

ক্র Adv. Diploma of Professional Game Development

ক্ল Cert IV in 3D Animation for Games and Film

Covered a broad range of computer science and visual design topics, including:

- Composition, layout and prototyping
- Realtime games programming in C++ (Visual Studio)
- 3D content creation and animation (3dsMax)
- Use of realtime graphics engines (Unreal)

Skills

HTML5/CSS3

5 years professional experience with modern web standards, client-side rendering, responsive design

Node.JS

Have used node for its build tooling/package ecosystem in production.

SASS

Have atomic-design structured SASS in production, with high browser compatibility.

Python

Gained a deep knowledge after using Python professionally for many years in server-side networking. It's my go-to choice for any trivial math/ logic problem, but I have experience using it at

Polymer

Currently giving Polymer 1.2 a good workout in a personal project, and would be stoked to use it at

C++

Long and deeply involved history with C++ at work, in personal projects and while studying games programming. Strong OOP design, multi-threaded/ high-performance disciplines, advanced use of

Bower

Good working knowledge of bower dependency management.

socket.io

Up to speed with socket.io 1.0 rooms, namespaces, binary encodings etc. Also have a deeper knowledge of the underlying mechanisms, i.e. websockets,

KnockoutIS

Extensive in-depth use, pushing the library to its performance limits and extending its capabilities.

Twisted

3+ years experience working with Twisted, including interfacing with C++ codebases using non-blocking RPC (WAMP) and other advanced usages.

lavascript

Experience with developing large, well structured IS codebases, with a growing knowledge of ES6/ES7 language features.

Backbone.is

Have developed and deployed backbone applications to production.

SOL

Experience writing SQL-backed apps - async/nonblocking and high-performance.

Git

Used extensively both professionally and personally. Have a solid understanding of underlying concepts.

iQuery

Used fairly comprehensively in the past.

Bootstrap

Used liberally in past work projects.

Coffeescript

Used pretty rigorously in a past personal project; would be delighted to use it again.

Gulp

Up to speed with writing and managing gulp tasks for optimization, deployment etc.

Gο

Covered briefly in a previous personal project. Certainly an enthusiast of Go and keen to put it to

Linux

Many years experience both personally and professionally. My ideal development environment is in Linux.